# **Kevin Ghorbani**

## Contact Information

www.kevinghorbani.com www.github.com/Kevin3727 www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-ghorbani kevin3727@gmail.com (608) 285-2834

List of Publications: inspirehep.net/author/profile/Kevin.Ghorbani.1

Legally authorized to work in the US for any employer

**Data Scientist** with experience in Quantitative Analysis, Big Data Queries, Data Mining, Statistics, Predictive Modeling, and Data Visualization. Worked with many types of large and complex datasets in the past 10 years in both small and large multinational teams.

#### **Education**

University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI

Ph.D., Physics - Data Analysis (May 2018)

Leiden University, Leiden, The Netherlands

M.S., Physics – Computational (January 2014)

**Sharif University of Technology**, Tehran, Iran

B.S., Physics (June 2011)

### **Experience**

WIPAC / University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI (2014 - present)

Research Assistant

- Produced an analysis with the tightest statistical constrains ever to discover a new elementary particle
- Cleaned noisy and inhomogeneous data taken by our detector at the south pole
- Increased the efficiency of event selections by over 100% using machine learning techniques; Implemented a novel technique to classify different types of events to was able to identify over 12,000 neutrino events per year of data (from previously 2,000 by the collaboration)
- Developed a new reconstruction model to increase energy resolution
- Utilized numerous statistical techniques, including sensitivity analysis, likelihood fitting, Bayesian statistics, hypothesis testing
- Worked with large datasets of O(100TB) per year of data, and massive computational processes on CPU and GPU clusters

Lorentz Institute, Leiden, NL (2012 - 2014)

Research Assistant

- Produced complex Monte Carlo simulations and studied cosmic strings
- Created a model to predict cosmic strings' behavior during interactions

**Institute for Research in Fundamental Sciences**, Tehran, IR (2008-2011)

Researcher

- Data reduction of raw images from Hubble Space Telescope and cleaning noisy data to retrieved useful information
- Analyzing galactic image channels to determine their properties via photometry
- Performing statistical analysis on cluster data to obtain dark matter properties

# Programing Skills

Languages: Expert: Python, C/C++, SQL, Shell script, Prior-experience: R, Matlab, HTML

**Machine Learning Techniques:** *Expert:* AdaBoost, Regression, Decision Tree, Random Forest, Support Vector Machine using scikit-learn, TensorFlow and Keras

**Tools:** Expert: NumPy, SciPy, pandas, Matplotlib, Jupyter notebook, Subversion, Git, condor, UNIX/Linux, *Prior-experience*: Flask

Other
Data Science

**Detector Data Calibration:** Performed data calibration using statistical methods to adjust latest models of antarctic ice

**Projects** 

**Travel Web App:** Developed a web app (using Google maps APIs) and developed machine learning regressors to predict travel time at given time in New York City and achieved accuracy of few minutes

**Chicago Crime Analysis:** Analyzed Chicago crime rate over 15 years of police data in order to explain the recent increase in the city's homicide rate and its relation to police activities

**Teaching Programing:** Teaching Python and machine learning to graduate students and post-doctoral researchers

Honors and Awards Research Assistantship – WIPAC (2014-present) Groesbeek-Assenbroek Scholarship (2013) Curatorenfonds Universiteit (2012 and 2013)

Leiden University Excellence Scholarship - Golden Award (2012 and 2013)